A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Arts and Humanities Program Files, Marcia T. Thompson FA1482
Rockefeller Archive Center
- National Arts Stabilization Fund (NASF), 1970-1994; 4
  - Correspondence and Meeting Materials, 1983-1993 (Box 34, Folder 274)
    Overview of The Kreisberg Group, Ltd.
    Worcester Art Museum correspondence
    Chairman's Agenda and Exhibits - 6/83
    Correspondence with Susan Berresford
  - National Arts Stabilization Fund (NASF) - RGAs, Finance Committee Report, News Clippings, Memos, and Correspondence (2 folders), 1984-1994 (Box 34, Folder 275-276)
  - National Arts Stabilization Fund (NASF) - The First Phase (2 copies), 1987 October (Box 34, Folder 277)
  - Marcia T. Thompson, Vice Chairman, National Arts Stabilization Fund (NASF) - Correspondence (2 folders), 1986-1994 (Box 34, Folder 278-279)
  - National Arts Stabilization Fund - Funding Models (2 folders), 1983-1984 (Box 34, Folder 280-281)
  - National Arts Stabilization Fund - Policy and Planning Committee, 1983-1989 (Box 34, Folder 282)
  - National Arts Stabilization Fund (NASF) Board - Yale School of Drama - Final Exam, 1981 May (Box 35, Folder 283)
  - Ford Foundation Pre-National Arts Stabilization Fund (NASF), 1970-1985 (Box 35, Folder 284)
  - National Arts Stabilization Fund (NASF) - Financial Accounting Standard Board (FASB) (2 folders), 1988-1994 (Box 35, Folder 285-286)
  - National Arts Stabilization Fund (NASF) - Correspondence, 1977-1988 (Box 35, Folder 287)
  - National Arts Stabilization Fund (NASF) - Publications, Proposals, Correspondence (3 folders), 1989-1993 (Box 35, Folder 288-290)
    Proposal to Pennsylvania Ballet
    Denver Symphony Orchestra
    National Arts Stabilization Fund (NASF): Restructuring Arizona's Arts Institutions by Glenn Peters
    Publications List
    Worcester Art Museum case statement
    Proposal to Pennsylvania Ballet, September 1989
    Contribution Bonds: A Development Campaign Security Program, For Universities and Colleges
    Photos - DeCordova and Dana Museum and Park, Marcia Thompson and John B. French
  - Ford Foundation - National Arts Stabilization Fund (NASF), Applications, Reports (4 folders), 1981-1989 (Box 35, Folder 291-292, Box 36, Folder 293-294)
  - National Arts Stabilization Fund (NASF) - Staff Memos, Responses, Fax Materials, 1983-1993 (Box 36, Folder 295)
  - Marcia T. Thompson Correspondence and Meeting Materials - President of National Arts Stabilization Fund (NASF), 1981-1988 (Box 36, Folder 296)
  - National Arts Stabilization Fund - Background, Strategies, Awards (2 folders), 1992-1993 (Box 36, Folder 297-298)
    National Arts Stabilization Fund Index
    Tab 1: NASF Background Statement
    Tab 2: Development of a Local Project
    Tab 3: The Stabilization Grant Process
    Tab 4: Preliminary Criteria for Participation
    Tab 5: Awards Announced as of December 31, 1992
    Tab 6: Nominees by Project Site
    Tab 7: Nominees by Discipline
    Tab 8: Board of Directors
    Tab 9: Growth: Comments and Observations
    Tab 10: New York City Loan Initiative
    Tab 11: Quarterly Progress Report - New York City Project
    Tab 12: Typical Request for Grant Action (Alvin Ailey)
    Tab 13: Typical Letter and Terms and Conditions of Grant (Alvin Ailey)
    Tab 14: Typical NASF Awards Release (Intiman)
    Tab 15: Selected News Coverage
  - National Arts Stabilization Fund (NASF) - Meeting of the Board of Directors - Minutes, Correspondence, Clippings, Theatre Communications Group Publications (3 folders), 1983-1992 (Box 36, Folder 299-301)
  - National Arts Stabilization Fund (NASF) - Awards and Nominations Newsletter Edits, 1990 (Box 37, Folder 302)
  - National Arts Stabilization Fund (NASF) - Financial Database, 1987 April (Box 37, Folder 303)
  - National Arts Stabilization Fund (NASF) - Leadership Alliances, 1980-1994 (Box 37, Folder 304)
  - National Arts Stabilization Fund (NASF) - Job Descriptions, 1989-1993 (Box 37, Folder 305)
  - National Arts Stabilization Fund (NASF) - Board of Directors Meeting, 1983-1986 (Box 37, Folder 306)
- Ford Foundation Board of Trustees, 1955-1992; 5
  Ford Foundation Board of Trustees meeting materials related to Ford initiatives in the arts and humanities.
  - Board of Trustees Meeting, 1971 March (Box 37, Folder 307)
    Symphony Mellon
    Symphony Ford Foundation
    Stabilization
    Endowment Grants
    Boston
    Conservatories
  - Meeting of the Board of Trustees, 1980 March (Box 37, Folder 308)
  - Trustees Committee of the Arts (2 folders), 1975-1980 (Box 37, Folder 309-310)
  - Shereff, Friedman, Hoffman and Goodman - Board Meeting Minutes (Drafts) (4 folders), 1972-1992 (Box 37, Folder 311, Box 38, Folder 312-314)
  - Board of Trustees - Catalogues Program Background, 1967-1977 (Box 38, Folder 315)
    Appropriations and DAP
    Fact Sheet/Letters/Budgets and Report Forms
    Grants Awarded
    Published/To Be Evaluated
    Catalogues Evaluated
    Applications Rejected
    Collections and Interest
    Sample Advertising Plan
  - Trustees Committee Meeting - Office of the Arts, 1975 December 11 (Box 38, Folder 316)
  - Faculty Salaries Hospital Support Medical Education, A Statement by the Trustees of the Ford Foundation, Special Appropriations, 1955 December 8-10 (Box 38, Folder 317)
  - Office of the Arts - Supplement to June 25, 1975 - Trustee Committee Meeting, 1975 July 31 (Box 38, Folder 318)
  - Information Paper for the Trustees Committee on Education and Public Policy - The Arts Program, 1980 March (Box 38, Folder 319)
  - Ford Foundation Board of Trustees/Future Program Planning Project/1976 - Staff Responses to Alexander Heard's September 24 Memorandum, "Next Steps in Planning for the Foundation's Future" - Volume I and II, 1976 November (Box 39, Folder 320-321)
  - Grants-in-Aid Programs, 1958-1971 (Box 39, Folder 322)
  - Grants-in-Aid - Fact Sheets, Letters, Awards, 1958-1965 (Box 39, Folder 323)
  - Grants-in-Aid - Materials, 1958-1969 (Box 39, Folder 324)
  - Grant-in-Aid - Programs and Statistics, 1966-1974 (Box 39, Folder 325)
    A/I Program
    Choral Directors
    Concert Artists
    Concert Soloists
    Creative Writers
    Cur. Training
    Directors Program
    Film Makers
    Opera Singers
    Poets and Fiction Writers Program
    Playwrights Prog.
    Theater Design
    Visual Artists
- Humanities and the Arts Program Files, 1953-1986; 6
  Grant files, reports, news clipping, administrative files, correspondence, and financial materials related to the activities of the Ford Foundation's work in the arts and humanities.
  - Ford Foundation Arts History, 1957-1983 (Box 40, Folder 326)
  - Education and Public Policy and Humanities and the Arts FY 1957-1981 (3 folders), 1957-1982 (Box 40, Folder 327-329)
    Statistics - Miscellaneous
    Ford Foundation Financial Statements
  - Office of the Arts FY 1957-1975 (Box 40, Folder 330)
  - Roger Kennedy - Members of the Arts Committee, 1978-1981 (Box 40, Folder 331)
  - The Arts in the United States: Inflation, Recession, and Public Policy, 1975 (Box 40, Folder 332)
  - Humanities and the Arts - Lists, undated (Box 40, Folder 333)
    Lists of Individuals:
    New York City - Music, Dance, Creative Writing
    Boston and Cambridge
    Worcester, Massachusetts
    New Haven
    Dallas
    Philadelphia
    Baltimore
    Washington, D.C.
    Virginia
    Atlanta
    Florida
    New Orleans
    Cleveland
    Cincinnati
    Indianapolis and Bloomington
    Chicago
    Milwaukee
    Detroit and Ann Arbor
    Minnesota
    Iowa City
    Urbana, Illinois
    St. Louis
    Kansas City
    Nebraska
    Oklahoma
    Houston, Texas
    Austin, Texas
    San Antonio
    New Mexico
    Tucson
    Los Angeles and vicinity
    San Francisco (including Oakland, Berkeley, Palo Alto)
    Salt Lake City
    Denver
    Portland
    Seattle
    New York City
  - Humanities and the Arts - Statistics, 1972-1975 (Box 41, Folder 334)
  - Arts Papers - June 1981 Trustees Meeting (4 folders), 1980-1981 (Box 41, Folder 335-338)
  - Funding of the Arts from Sources Other Than the Ford Foundation (3 folders), 1975-1981 (Box 41, Folder 339-341)
  - Committee on the Future of the Arts, 1978-1980 (Box 42, Folder 342)
  - Outline of Arts Paper for the Trustees, 1981 (Box 42, Folder 343)
  - Roger G. Kennedy Memos to Arts Committee, 1978 (Box 42, Folder 344)
  - National Endowment for the Arts - Correspondence and Proposals, 1971 (Box 42, Folder 345)
  - Richard C. Sheldon - Support of the Arts, 1978 November (Box 42, Folder 346)
  - Humanities and Arts Program Staff - Lowry Miscellaneous Memoranda (3 folders), 1967-1974 (Box 42, Folder 347-349)
  - Humanities and the Arts Program Staff - Marcia Thompson File, 1953-1980 (Box 42, Folder 350)
  - Humanities and the Arts Program Staff - Richard Kapp Miscellaneous Memoranda, 1970-1977 (Box 42, Folder 351)
  - Humanities and the Arts Program Staff - Lowry, W. McNeil, 1964-1975 (Box 43, Folder 352)
    Biography and press release
  - Humanities and the Arts Program Staff - Lowry, W. McNeil - Personnel File, 1959-1964 (Box 55, Folder 458)
    Confidential material
  - The Ford Foundation Program in Humanities and the Arts (Publication), 1959 February (Box 43, Folder 353)
  - Ford Foundation Support for the Arts in the United States: A Discussion of New Emphases in the Foundation's Arts Program, A Working Paper from the Ford Foundation, 1986 August (Box 43, Folder 354)
  - Scholars' Work and Works, undated (Box 43, Folder 355)
  - Foundation for Humanities and the Arts, 1973-1974 (Box 43, Folder 356)
  - Foundation for Humanities and the Arts (FHA) - List of Incorporators, 1973-1978 (Box 43, Folder 357)
  - Memo to Members of Arts Committee from Roger G. Kennedy, 1978 February 22 (Box 43, Folder 358)
  - Why Bother About the Arts?, 1977 March (Box 43, Folder 359)
  - Review of the Arts - January 29, 1981 - Memos, 1976-1981 (Box 43, Folder 360)
  - The Arts Program, Information Paper for the Trustees Committee on Education and Public Policy, 1980 March (Box 43, Folder 361)
  - Statistics - Ford Foundation and the Arts, 1977-1978 (Box 43, Folder 362)
  - Support of the Arts, Richard C. Sheldon, 1978 November (Box 43, Folder 363)
  - Ford Arts Program Budget(s) - 1976 Budgets and Commitments, 1976 November 5 (Box 43, Folder 364)
  - Humanities and the Arts Committee Agenda (Mrs. Thompson), 1973 March 21 (Box 43, Folder 365)
  - Foundation for the Arts - W. McNeil Lowry, 1978-2000 (Box 43, Folder 366)
  - Humanities and the Arts Program Statistics (II) - Breakdown by Fiscal Years, 1957-1978 (Box 44, Folder 367)
  - Arts Organizations - Geographical Distribution/Founding - Dates 1915-1980 (Box 44, Folder 368)
  - Ford - Arts, 1974-1976 (Box 44, Folder 369)
  - Humanities and the Arts Program Statistics - Miscellaneous IX (4 folders), 1969-1978 (Box 44, Folder 370-373)
  - Ford Foundation - Education and Public Policy/Arts - General Clippings (2 folders), 1962-1981 (Box 45, Folder 374-375)
  - Ford Foundation: Humanities and the Arts - Editorials and Opinion Pieces, 1970-1974 (Box 45, Folder 376-377)
  - Ford Foundation - Division of Humanities and the Arts - European and International Activities, 1970 December 30 (Box 45, Folder 378)
  - Proposed Budget - Fiscal Years 1974 and 1975, 1973 June (Box 45, Folder 379)
  - The Finances of the Performing Arts Volume I - A Survey of 166 Professional Nonprofit Resident Theaters, Operas, Symphonies, Ballets, and Modern Dance Companies: A Ford Foundation Report, 1974 (Box 45, Folder 380)
  - The Finances of the Performing Arts Volume II - A Survey of the Characteristics and Attitudes of Audiences for Theater, Opera, Symphony, and Ballet in 12 U.S. Cities: A Report to the Ford Foundation, 1974 (Box 46, Folder 381)
  - Division of Humanities and the Arts - Patterns of Objectives and Grant Actions -- The Arts: Summary and Recapitulation, March 1957 - September 30, 1971, 1972 June (Box 46, Folder 382)
  - Arts Program, 1961-1975 (Box 46, Folder 383)
    Arts
    Education
    Humanities
    Division of the Humanities and the Arts
  - Grant Request - Humanities and the Arts, 1962 (Box 46, Folder 384)
  - Humanities and the Arts - Administrative Interns Program - Evaluation, 1974 (Box 46, Folder 385)
  - Humanities and Arts Discussion Papers - Binder 1 (2 folders), 1956 February-1972 June (Box 46, Folder 386-387)
    Titles include:
    Feb. 9, 1956 - Memorandum - W.M. Lowry: A Program of Philanthropic Support of the Humanities and Creative Arts
    Mar. 17-18, 1960 - An Enlarged Program in the Arts
    Spring, 1962 - Program Submission Concerning Future Program Activities/The Humanities
    Spring, 1962 - Program Submission Concerning Future Program Activities/The Arts
    Dec. 6, 1963 - Historic and Architectural Preservation and Restoration
    June, 1967 - Humanities and the Arts Division - Program Budget Request, Fiscal Year 1968
    June, 1967 - Ten-Year Program Review, 1957-1967
    Nov., 1968 - The Economic Crisis in the Arts: The Need for a National Policy
    Nov. 19, 1968 - Ford Foundation Strategy in the Arts - A Review
    May, 1970 - Some Considerations on Cost Effectiveness in the Performing Arts
    Mar. 25-26, 1971 - Excerpt from Docket: Humanities and the Arts Division Nonrenewable Grants in the Performing Arts
    Mar. 25-26, 1971 - Excerpt from Docket: Humanities and the Arts Division Cash Reserve Grants
    Sep. 15, 1971 - Cash Reserve Program
    June, 1972 - Patterns of Objectives and Grant Actions - the Arts Summary and Recapitulation (March 1957 - Sept. 1971)
  - Humanities and Arts Discussion Papers - Binder 2 (2 folders), 1972 June-1975 July (Box 47, Folder 388-389)
    June, 1972 - The Foundation and the Arts: The Decade of the Seventies
    June, 1972 - Program Trends for Discussion and Action - The Immediate Future
    June, 1975 - Proposed Budget, Fiscal Years 1976 and 1977
    June 25, 1975 - Trustee Arts Committee: I. Existing Cash Reserve Program; II. Program Procedures: Monitoring and Technical Assistance; III. Extension: Cash Reserve Program II
    July 31, 1975 - Trustee Arts Committee: Supplement to June 25, 1975 Paper
  - Humanities and Arts Discussion Papers - Binder 3 (2 folders), 1975 December-1979 November (Box 47, Folder 390-391)
    Dec. 11, 1975 - Office of the Arts: 1. Proposed Programs for Development of Talent and Art Forms; 2. Discussion of State and Community Arts Councils and Possible Foundation Support for their Support; 3. Supplemental Report on the Cash Reserve Program
    March, 1977 - Why Bother About the Arts?
    June, 1977 - The Arts in June
    March, 1978 - The American Classics Revisited
    Nov., 1978 - The Arts Office: A Two Year Report
    Nov. 20, 1979 - The Foundation's Arts Program
  - Humanities and Arts Discussion Papers - Binder 4 (3 folders), 1980 March-1981 September (Box 47, Folder 392, Box 48, Folder 393-394)
    March, 1980 - The Arts Program
    April 23, 1980 - Arts Income Management Management System: System Specifications
    July 7, 1980 - Memorandum - Harold Howe II Substitution for Cash Reserve Commitments
    July 10, 1980 - Arts Income Management System: System Specifications
    Sep., 1980 - The Education Program of the Ford Foundation
    Jan., 1981 - Education and Public Policy: Background Review of the Arts
    June, 1981 - The Arts and Culture in the Ford Foundation
    Sep. 23-25, 1981 - Docket - Board of Trustees
  - Humanities and Arts Discussion Papers - Binder 5 (2 folders), 1981 September-1983 December (Box 48, Folder 395-396)
    Sep. 23, 1981 - Docket - Education and Culture Committee
    March, 1982 - Education and Culture Committee: Binder 1: Preliminary Program Outline; Binder 2: A Supplement to Part II/Results
    Nov., 1982 - Education and Culture: Excellence and Equity for the 80's and Beyond
    Nov., 1982 - Education and Culture Committee: The Stabilization Strategy: A Proposed Private Sector Initiative for the 1980's
    Dec., 1982 - Board of Trustees: The Stabilization Strategy: A Proposed Private Sector Initiative for the 1980's
    March, 1983 - Proposed Spending Level, Budget and Preliminary Program Plans for FY 1984-85
    June, 1983 - National Arts Stabilization Fund
    Aug. 8, 1983 - Recommendation for Grant Action: National Arts Stabilization Fund - $237,193 for start-up expenses
    Dec. 8, 1983 - Recommendation for Grant Action: National Arts Stabilization Fund - $7,000,000
- Ford Foundation Stabilization Program, 1971-1993; 7
  The Ford Foundation Stabilization Program built upon the grant making strategies of the earlier Symphony Orchestra Program and the Cash Reserve Program and focused on financial reporting, financial planning, and balance sheet strategies. Eventually, a separate organization, the National Arts Stabilization Fund (NASF), was established from these strategies with the assistance of other funders like the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation and the Rockefeller Foundation. By 1981, grants totaling $27.6 million had been awarded by the Ford Foundation to 72 arts organizations. Participants in the Ford Stabilization Program included:
  Dance:
  Alvin Ailey American Dance Theater (NYC)
  American Ballet Theatre (NYC)
  Ballet West (Salt Lake City)
  Boston Ballet
  Cunningham Dance Foundation (NYC)
  Feld Ballet (NYC)
  Houston Ballet
  Joffrey Ballet (NYC)
  Murray Louis Dance Company (NYC)
  Nikolais Dance Theatre (NYC)
  North Carolina Dance Theater (Winston-Salem)
  Paul Taylor Dance Company *NYC)
  San Francisco Ballet
  Twyla Tharp Dance Foundation (NYC)
  Other:
  Big Apple Circus (NYC)
  Children's Art Carnival (NYC)
  North Carolina School of the Arts (Winston-Salem)
  Theater:
  A Contemporary Theater (Seattle)
  Acting Company (NYC)
  Actors Theatre of Louisville (KY)
  American Conservatory Theatre (San Francisco)
  American Place Theatre (NYC)
  American Shakespeare Theatre (Stratford, CT)
  Arena Stage (Washington, DC)
  Arizona Theatre Company (Tucson)
  Asolo State Theater (Sarasota, FL)
  Center Stage (Baltimore)
  Circle in the Square (NYC)
  Circle Repertory Company (NYC)
  Eugene O'Neill Theater Center (Waterford, CT)
  Folger Theatre Group (Washington, DC)
  Guthrie Theater (Minneapolis)
  Hartford Stage Company
  Indiana Repertory Theatre (Indianapolis)
  Long Wharf Theatre (New Haven)
  Manhattan Theatre Club (NYC)
  Mark Taper Forum (Los Angeles)
  McCarter Theatre (NYC)
  Negro Ensemble Company (NYC)
  New Federal Theatre (NYC)
  Oregon Shakespearean Festival (Ashland)
  PAF Playhouse (Huntington, NY)
  Playwrights Horizons (NYC)
  St. Louis, Repertory Theatre of
  St. Nicholas Theater Company (Chicago)
  Stage West (Springfield, MA)
  Studio Arena Theatre (Buffalo)
  Trinity Square Repertory Company (Providence, RI)
  Opera:
  Baltimore Opera Company
  Boston, Opera Company of
  Chicago, Lyric Opera of
  Cincinnati Opera
  Dallas Opera
  Fort Worth Opera
  Houston Grand Opera
  Kansas City, Lyric Opera of (MO)
  Kentucky Opera (Louisville)
  Lake George Opera Festival (NY)
  Michigan Opera Theatre (Detroit)
  Minnesota Opera (Minneapolis)
  New Orleans Opera
  New York City Opera
  Portland Opera (OR)
  St. Louis, Opera Theatre of
  St. Paul Opera
  San Diego Opera
  San Francisco Opera
  Santa Fe Opera (NM)
  Seattle Opera
  Spring Opera of San Francisco
  Washington Opera (DC)
  Western Opera Theater (San Francisco)
  - Ford Foundation Stabilization Analysis, 1981-1985 (Box 48, Folder 397)
  - Ford Foundation Stabilization Program - Strategy, 1971-1981, 1977-1988 (Box 48, Folder 398)
  - Ford Foundation Stabilization Program - Defaults/Modifications/Terminations, 1981-1985 (Box 48, Folder 399)
  - Ford Foundation Stabilization Grants IV - Other, 1971-1984 (Box 48, Folder 400)
  - Ford Foundation Stabilization Grants, 1986-1988 (Box 48, Folder 401)
  - Ford Foundation Stabilization - Comments I & II, 1975-1987 (Box 49, Folder 402)
    Arrangement
    Sorted alphabetically
  - Ford Foundation Stabilization Program Results and Statistics, 1971-1984 (Box 49, Folder 403)
  - Ford Foundation Stabilization Grants I - Dance (2 folders), 1971-1986 (Box 49, Folder 404-405)
  - Ford Foundation Stabilization Program - Outside Affiliations, 1978-1986 (Box 49, Folder 406)
  - Ford Foundation Stabilization - Results and Findings, 1971-1983 (Box 49, Folder 407)
  - Ford Foundation Stabilization Program - Grants Records Chronological (2 folders), 1971-1974 (Box 49, Folder 408, Box 50, Folder 409)
  - Ford Foundation Stabilization Program - Grants Records Chronological (2 folders), 1975-1982 (Box 50, Folder 410-411)
  - Stabilization Program - Announcements/Ford Foundation Letter and Grantee Press Releases A-Z (2 folders), 1971-1983 (Box 50, Folder 412-413)
  - Stabilization Grantees - At-a-Glance Base Year vs. Grant End, 1971-1981 (2 folders), 1981-1993 (Box 51, Folder 414-415)
    Ford Foundation Programs I and II At-a-Glance Index (46 tabs in folder):
    1. A Contemporary Theatre
    2. American Ballet Theatre
    3. Arena Stage
    4. Arizona Theatre Company
    5. Ballet West
    6. Baltimore Opera
    7. Big Apple Circus
    8. Boston Ballet
    9. Boston, Opera Company of
    10. Center Stage
    11. Children's Art Carnival
    12. Cincinnati Opera
    13. Cleveland Playhouse
    14. Cunningham Dance Foundation
    15. Feld Ballet
    16. Folger Theatre Group
    17. Fort Worth Opera
    18. Hartford Stage Company
    19. Houston Ballet
    20. Houston Grand Opera
    21. Joffrey Ballet (missing)
    22. Lake George Opera
    23. Long Wharf Theatre
    24. Louis Dance Company, Murray
    25. Manhattan Theatre Club
    26. Michigan Opera
    27. Negro Ensemble
    28. New England Conservatory of Music
    29. New York City Ballet
    30. New York City Opera (missing)
    31. Nikolais Dance Company, Alwin
    32. North Carolina Dance Theatre
    33. North Carolina School of the Arts
    34. O'Neill Theatre Center
    35. Opera Theatre of Saint Louis
    36. Oregon Shakespearean Festival
    37. Repertory Theatre of Saint Louis
    38. San Diego Opera
    39. San Francisco Ballet
    40. San Francisco Opera Association
    41. Santa Fe Opera
    42. Seattle Opera
    43. Stage West
    44. Taper (Mark) Forum
    45. Taylor Dance Company, Paul
    46. Tharp Dance Foundation, Twyla
  - Ford Foundation Stabilization Grants II - Opera (2 folders), 1984-1986 (Box 51, Folder 416-417)
    Tab index:
    1. Baltimore Opera Company
    2. Boston, Opera Company of
    3. Chicago, Lyric Opera of
    4. Cincinnati Opera
    5. Dallas Opera
    6. Fort Worth Opera
    7. Houston Grand Opera
    8. Kansas City, Lyric Opera of
    9. Kentucky Opera (Louisville)
    10. Lake George Opera Festival (NY)
    11. Michigan Opera Theater (Detroit)
    12. Minnesota Opera (Minneapolis)
    13. New Orleans Opera
    14. New York City Opera
    15. Portland Opera (OR)
    16. St. Louis, Opera Theatre of
    17. St. Paul Opera
    18. San Diego Opera
    19. San Francisco Opera
    20. Santa Fe Opera (NM)
    21. Seattle Opera
    22. Spring Opera of San Francisco
    23. Washington Opera (DC)
    24. Western Opera Theater (San Francisco)
  - Ford Foundation Stabilization Grants III - Theater (3 folders), 1984-1988 (Box 51, Folder 418-419, Box 52, Folder 420)
    Tab Index:
    1. A Contemporary Theater (Seattle)
    2. Acting Company (NYC)
    3. Actor Theatre of Louisville (KY)
    4. American Conservatory Theater
    5. American Place Theatre (NYC)
    6. American Shakespeare Theatre
    7. Arena Stage (DC)
    8. Arizona Theatre Company
    9. Asolo State Theatre (FL)
    10. Center Stage (Baltimore)
    11. Cincinnati Playhouse in the Park
    12. Circle in the Square (NYC)
    13. Circle Repertory Company (NYC)
    14. Cleveland Play House
    15. Eugene O'Neill Theater Center
    16. Folger Theatre Group (DC)
    17. Guthrie Theater
    19. Indiana Repertory Theatre
    20. Long Wharf Theatre
    21. Manhattan Theatre Club
    22. Mark Taper Forum
    23. McCarter Theatre (NJ)